

TIMOTHEE PESTEL

timothee-pestel

timpstl

DevOps Engineer

- <u>timothee.pestel.pro@gmail.com</u>
- +33 6 59 69 74 12

CAREER SUMMARY

After various experiences as IT/Application Administrator and Security Consultant, I have been specializing on DevOps and **Cloud** for more than 2 years.

I am now looking for new challenges on huge projects, with great open source and cloud culture and with hardly motivated people.

WORK EXPERIENCE

DevOps Engineer Ercom/Thales

2018 - Present

As a member of the DevOps team of 3 people, I work on the infrastructure architecture design, the build, the deployment and the run of the applications **Citadel Team** & **Cryptobox**

- Define, Deploy and Run 24/7 SaaS infrastructures
- · Manage infrastructure and software monitoring
- · Automate software tests and deployments
- Attend and present work to team meetings
- Technological Watch

Biggest Achievements:

- Deploy Cryptobox on AWS and Azure AKS
- Create Cryptobox Helm Chart
- Migrate Citadel Team from Docker to Kubernetes (Helm)
- Set up Citadel Team CI/CD tools and workflow

Technologies used:

Openstack AWS Azure Docker Kubernetes Helm GitLab CI/CD **PostgresSQL** StorageOS Python

Cyber Risk & Security Consultant

Beijaflore

2017 - 2018

Mission at ENGIE - Audit and Consulting for ENGIE's industrial entities

- Deployment of a Lab dedicated to industrial attacks demonstrations
- Windows Hardening
- SIEM scenarii definitions and technical translation
- ISO 27001 audit fonctionnel et technique
- Web Application pentesting
- Technical RSSI supports
- Deployment of a Lab dedicated to industrial attacks demonstrations

Technologies used:

Windows

Fortinet

Stormshield

Kali Linux

Burp

Splunk

Syslog

Nessus Tenable

2014 - 2017

Mission at Orange - Mobile application Production Engineer (6 months)

- Platform base infrastructure management
- Micro services deployments from Q&A to Production
- Load Testing
- · Production incidents management

Mission at Orange - Data Mobile Production Engineer (18 months)

- Incident management
- High level customer support
- Schedule production operation management
- Day to day tools and scripts improvements
- Judicial requisitions researches

Technologies used:



SKILLS & TOOLS



EDUCATION

Engineering Degree

ISEP

2009 - 2014

CERTIFICATIONS (IN PROGRESS)

Certified Sysadmin

Linux Foundation

T Certified Kubernetes Administrator

Linux Foundation

LANGUAGE

French (Native)

English (Professional)

INTERESTS

Running

Workout

Sciences & Technology

Tennis

Horse Riding

Motorcycling

Designed with ♥ by Xiaoying Riley for developers Print PDF